Guide to the Martin Gardner Papers SC0647
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Game files, Series 1
  - String, 2 folder(s)
    - 1962, December, 1962-1997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Notes on murder mystery: "Leopard Cat's Cradle", by Jerome Barry
      String Releases (type of magic trick)
      Katz, Max
    - Aragon's Poem, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Many answers
      Christmas greetings
      End of strings article
      Pauling, Linus
      Burton, Dennis
  - Tangent Circles, 10 folder(s)
    - 1979, January, 1978-1979 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Packing Circles, Touching Circles, 1964-1978 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      Original article (complete)
      Analysis by Philip Jackson, Donald Davies
      Jackson, Philip
      Davies, Donald
      Pedoe, Dan
    - Circles to Squares (& Rectangles), 1978 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Circles to Circles, 1959-1990 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Material from Schaer (Check for Book), 1978 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      Schaer, J.
      Jepsen, Charles
    - Arbelos, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Golomb's Coins, 1973-1979 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      [Perfect square of 21 smaller squares, in Golomb letter]
    - From Ron G., 1978 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      2 articles by Ron Graham, & pages of article in German
    - Malgatti Problem, 1967-1968 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      4 articles by Michael Goldberg
    - Circles to Triangles, 1979-1981 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Tasks That End, 5 folder(s)
    - 1983, April, 1982-1983 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      Correspondance (with Scientific American) on MG plans.
      Misc. articles & notes.
    - Hydra Problem, 1982-1983 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      Lots of papers/articles.
      Dershowitz, Nachum
      Manna, Zohar
    - Bulgarian Solitaire, 1982-1984 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      Lots of MG notes.
      Bressoad, David (to Knuth)
      Nadvorney, Leo
      Brandt, Jorgen
    - K (K-1) "Proofs", 1983-1984 (Box 53, Folder 13)
      Weiss, Benjamin
      Brenner, Charles
      Lindsey II, John
      Akin, Ethan
      Burhart, Frank
      Farjon, David
      Marshal, Ian
      Iguca, Kiyoshi
    - 18-Spot Problem (Graham & Berlekamp), 1976 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Taxicab Geometry, 2 folder(s)
    - 1980, November [ 1 of 2], 1980-1981 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      Lotes of short articles
      Krause, Eugene
      Abbott, Ken
    - 1980, November [ 2 of 2], undated (Box 51, Folder 16)
      Complete answers to "Taxicab Geometry" book, by Eugene Krause.
  - Ternary System
    - 1964, May, 1961-1964 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Anagram Puzzle (Sprague's Switching Problem)
      Heyl, Edgar
  - Tetraflexigons, 3 folder(s)
    - 1958, May, 1958-1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Ron Edward's "Monstrosity", a right-angle flexagon (model and instructions)
      models intermixed with letters
      Platt, Charles
      Deupree, Richard (systematic theory)
      Pook, L.P. (with many models)
      Holmes, Duane (Ring Structure)
      Jones, P.H.
      Dukich, Thomas
    - Tetraflexigons [2 of 2], 1972-1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      many articles, magic tricks and models intermixed
      "Self-Designing Tetraflexagons", by Bob Neale
      "What Comes First?", by Bob Neale (paperfold routine)
      Flexicubes, in Pook letter.
      Pook, L.P.
      Flexicubes
    - Flexitube, 1955-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Ming, Vong
      Edwards, Ron
      Whitney, James
      Wood, George
      Stone, A.H. (with analysis)
  - Tetrahedron, 4 folder(s)
    - 1965, February (Box 14, Folder 4)
      "Three Structures by Buckminster Fuller in the Garden of the Museum of Modern Art, New York" (1959) (Poster/Booklet)
      Marengo, Norman
    - Tetrahedra - Paper Models, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Alexander G. Bell, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Museum
    - Tetrahedron Magic Trick, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Tetrahexes & Tetraboloes, 2 folder(s)
    - 1967, June (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Article; see folders
    - Proofs of Tower Uniqueness, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Many (similar) proofs
      Holt, Machael
  - The 24 Color Triangles, 2 folder(s)
    - 1968, October, 1961-1995 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      Many examples, theory.
      Trimino, Trifolia, Multi-Match III instructions (from Kadon Ent.)
      Contack (Parker Brothers game, in letter)
      Coster, Ora & Theo
      Parker Brothers, Inc
      Jonas, E.C.
      Jones, Kathy
      Haubrich, Jacques
    - Conway's 27-cube Puzzles (& Trigg's), 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - The Hypercube, 5 folder(s)
    - 1966, November (Box 17, Folder 14)
      just article (see 4D Geometry folder)
    - Unfolding the Hypercube, 1961-1980 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      Levy-Leblond, J.M.
      Schmidt, Eric
      Vidal, Claudio
    - Hypercube, 1966-1974 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      "The Ifth of Oofth", by Walter Tevis (Sci. Fi. story from Galaxy Mag, Apr, 1957)
      Ways to draw a hypercube
      Barton, Hiram
    - Correct Solution to Max. Cubes in Hypercube, 1966-2000 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      "Partial Solution to the Largest m-Cube in an n-cube", by Kay DeVicci (typescript)
      Other solutions in the various letters below, summary in Guy's letter.
      Baer, Hermann
      De Jong, G. de Josselin
      Bosch, Eugen
      DeVicci, Kay
    - Prince Rupert's Hypercube Problem, 1960-2000 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      Various solutions which disagree with each other
  - The Infinite Regress
    - 1965, April (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - The Planiverse, 5 folder(s)
    - 1980, July [1 of 2], 1976-1996 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      Some "early" history & articles by Dewdney
      Jackiw, Roman
    - 1980, July [2 of 2], undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
      Mostly articles, reviews, ads, ...
      "Micro-Ecology in a Small Stream", by A.K. Dewdney (booklet) 1996
    - Planiverse Ideas from Readers, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      Many ideas, designs, etc.
      Stewart, Ian
    - Abbott's Flatland, 1980-1983 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      Ads & pictures of Arion Press version of Flatland.
    - Henle's Linear Go (Pinch) (& Other Linear Games), 1971-1980 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      Linear Go (Henle), 1D Checkers (MG), 1D Chess
  - The Supperellipse, 4 folder(s)
    - 1965, September, 19651988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Magazine: "Dansk Kunsthaandvaerk 4", Aug. 1964 (Danish)
      Magazine: "inspiration 68" (Danish/English) - filed elsewhere
      "King of Supershape", by Anne Chamberlin (photocopy of Esquire article, Jan ?)
      "close-up, Piet Hein Bestrides Art & Science, A Poet With a Slie Rule", by Jim Hicks (photocopy)
    - Furniture, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Magazine articles, mostly Danish
    - On Center of Curve & Other New Properties, 1965-1976 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Van Ammers, Anthony
      Hogan, Bill
      Cundy, Martyn
    - Lame Curves (other exponents), 1965-1967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Muses, Charles
      Frey, harvey
      Shelton, J. Paul
  - Tictacktoe
    - 1957, March (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tiling Plane with Polygons, 6 folder(s)
    - 1975, July [1 of 2], 1969-1977 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      3,4,5,6 sides
      Hirshhorn, Michael
      Szekeros, George
    - Tiling Plane with Polygons [2 of 2], 1976-1986 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Niven, Ivan
      Rice, Marjorie
    - Kershner - Papers, Letters, 1975-1976 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      Information on how he did analysis on pentagonal tilings, where he made mistakes, and some suggestions on how it should be done
    - James New Pentagon!, 1975-1977 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      Analysis by Doris Schattschneider
      Bomford, Tony
      James III, Richard E.
    - Mrs. Rice's Patterns, 1976-1978 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      Rice's original drawings
      comparison (by Schattschneider) of Rice & Kershner, and much analysis
      (Note on Ammann's tiling in Schattschneider letter of 4 May, 1976)
    - Doris Schattschneider, 1975-1979 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      Details of history of pentagonal tilings interspersed in correspondance. Also several of her papers on pentagonal tiling.
  - Tiling with Polyominoes, etc., 5 folder(s)
    - 1975, August, 1975-1978 (Box 33, Folder 13)
      "Puzzles for Christmas", by L.S. Penrose & Roger Penrose (reprint)
      Error in statement of Conway Criterion
      A Robert Reid tiling (with septominoes)
    - Polyomino tiling, 1965-1975 (Box 33, Folder 14)
      Lots of results and examples
      Bishop, Gregory
      Conlan, Jim
    - Alternate Square and "Bracket" Heptomino, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 15)
      Lots of variations of tiling
      "A Generalized Theory of Divisibility", by Solomon Golomb (preliminary typescript, 1980)
    - Polyiamond Tiling, 1965-1996 (Box 33, Folder 16)
      Lots of examples & theorems on polyiamond tilings
      Wichman, Brian
    - Polyhex Tiling, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      Just a letter and drawings of tilings through 5 (pentahexes?)
  - Time Stopping
    - 1979, March, 1979-1988 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      "The Nature of Time", by Henry Lambert
      "An Investigation of Hypertime Physics", by Frank Drummond (typescript)
  - Time Travel, 5 folder(s)
    - 1974, May, 1974-1994 (Box 29, Folder 17)
      Notes & Short articles & adds for T.T. books (and limericks)
      Audio tape: J. Richard Gott & Paul Nahin with Ira Flatow on "Talk of the Nation" (Science Friday), NPR program. (About 10 minutes of Car tAlk at beginning; Mathematics interview at end.)
      Sagan, Carl
      Park, David
    - T.T. in Fiction, Drama, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      Lots of references plus a few stories
      "Who's Cribbing", by Jack Lewis
      "The Killer", by J. T. Oliver
      Propp, James
    - Time Travel Articles [1 of 2], 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 19)
      Many articles, popular, philosophical, scientific (1953-1989)
      Horwich, Paul
      Meiland, Jack
    - Time Travel Articles [2 of 2], 1974-1998 (Box 29, Folder 20)
      More articles (1974-2000)
      Weitzel, Donald
    - My Old Time Travel Stroy, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Notes on time travel (by MG)
      Story, with anotations: "Lost Blue Eyes", by MG (typescript)
  - Topological Models
    - 1957, June (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Curious figures descended from the Moebius Band
      Photos of wood models
  - Topological Recreations
    - 1958, October (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Gale (game)
      Pencil Straw and Shoe String (Stewart Judah)
      ring on Card puzzle
      Network tracing puzzle
      Ring Tie (Eddie Joseph)
      Grant, U.F.
      Judah, Stewart
  - Topology, 3 folder(s)
    - 1963, July [1 of 2], 1953-1983 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Many articles, some science fiction stories
      Two "Trimobius" handkerchiefs, in separate envelope
      Tuckerman, L (from MG)
      Encyclopedia Britannica
      Leverett, Bill
      Pitzel, Michael
    - Topology [2 of 2], 1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Marynov, Saken
    - Klein Bottle and Cross Cap, 1963-1999 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      Notes on paper models
      Stoll, Cliff
      Harrison, Kent
      Chaplin, Albin
  - Trapdoor Ciphers, 15 folder(s)
    - 1977, August, 1977-1988 (Box 40, Folder 15)
      Partial article
      Some articles from "Cryptologia" magazine on Poe's cipher
      Many readers solutions to Poe cipher
      Various newspaper & magazine articles on cryptography
      Rivest, Ronald
      Winkel, Brian
    - Lattice Ciphers, undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
      Article: "Hiding in Lattices", by Ivars Peterson (Science News, Vo. 152, July 5, 1997
    - Biham & Shamir (DEA - Defective Fault Analysis), undated (Box 40, Folder 17)
      Photocopy of New Scientist article from 9 Nov, 1996, "'Unbreakable' Code Cracked Wide Open", by Robert Mathews
    - Big Numbers, 1992-1993 (Box 40, Folder 18)
      "Big Numbers & Little Secrets: PUblic Key Encriptography For the Hobbyist", by T. Kaliszewski, 1982 (book with floppy disk)
      Kaliszewski, T.
    - Articles [1 of 2], 1984 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Articles [2 of 2], undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - News Reports, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Rivest, et. al. [1 of 2], 1977-1994 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Much correspondence between MG & Rivest, along wiht several papers by Rivest & others.
      A packet of materials from RSA Data Security, Inc.
    - Rivest, et. al. [2 of 2], undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
      More articles, papers, announcements, newsletters, etc, on RSA encryption
    - Cracking SA Message RSA-129, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
      Mostly articles, from newspapers and magazines
    - Diffie & Hillman, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      Long articles & papers by and about Diffie-Hillman
    - Merkle [1 of 2], 1977 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      Mostly version 8 of "Secure Communications over Insecure Channels", by Ralph Merkle, 28 pages (paper)
    - Merkle [2 of 2], 1979 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      Secrecy, Authentication, and Public Key Systems", by Ralph Charles Merkle, June, 1979, Technical Report No. 1979-1, I.F.S Stanford
    - Simmons, 1977-1983 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Spinoffs, 1978-1979 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      Tossing a coin by mail
      Dice by mail
      Poker by mail (inspired by dice)
      Zero knowledge proffs!
      Computer network security
      "Mental Poker", by Adi Shamir, Ronald Rivest, Leonard Adleman, 1978 (typescript)
      "The Albanian Generals Problem", by L. Lamport et.al., 1979 (SRI International Report CSL-97)
      Floyd, Robert
      Lamport, Leslie
  - Tree Graphs
    - 1968, February (Box 19, Folder 23)
      Kruskal, Joseph
      Prentiss, Thomas
  - Tree-Plants (N in a Row), 4 folder(s)
    - 1976, August [1 of 2], 1973-1976 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Photocopies of puzzle from 1821 book by John Jackson
      Macmillan, R.H.
    - 1976, August [2 of 2], 1976-2000 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      Van Teeseling, Tom
      Farrell, Jeremiah
    - Material Relating to Tree-Plant Patterns, 1967-1976 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Legard's game
      Legard, A.R.
    - History U.S. Flag, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      Pictures of early flags.
  - Triangle, 3 folder(s)
    - 1970, June, 1958-1970 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Five-con Triangle's ("Almost Congruent"), undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
      Articles
    - Spot & Equilateral Triangle, 1967-1986 (Box 22, Folder 26)
      "Circus Triangles", by Herbert Grimsey & Donald Entwisle (photocopy of typescript)
      Grimsey, A.H.R.
  - Trisection, 3 folder(s)
    - 1966, June [1 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Trisection [2 of 2], 1970-1977 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Crank Trisection, 1974-1987 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      Dudley, Underwood
  - Trivalent Graphs, 8 folder(s)
    - 1976, April, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      Incomplete column
    - Published Papers on Snarks [1 of 2], 1976-1980 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      Many papers, offprints, typescripts, etc.
      Beraha, Sami
      Secrest, Don
    - Published Papers on Snarks [2 of 2], 1976-1996 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      More articles, etc
    - The Graph "Super Task", 1976 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      Kaufman, richard
    - Isaacs' Letters, 1975-1978 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      Rufus Isaacs
      Rufus' correspondence with various letter writers, on Snarks
    - Corrections (Federico), undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
      Photocopy of (original S.A.) article
      Several (old) articles, referenced in Federico letter
    - REader Response on Snarks, 1976-1979 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      Wilson, Robin
      Thomas, J.M.
    - The Hamiltonian Path, etc., 1976 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - TTT
    - 1971, August, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Ticktacktoe (see separate TTT folder)
      Just the article (not complete)
  - Turing Machines & Game
    - 1971, June, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Unit Fractions (Reciprocals) (Egyptian), 3 folder(s)
    - 1978, October [1 of 3], 1980 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      Many articles on unit fractions
      "Egyption Fractions", by Nicola Franceschine, III, Thisis (Sonoma State) 1978
      Wells, David
    - 1978, October [2 of 3], 1978-1979 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Many readers letters with examples.
    - 1978, October [3 of 3], 1980-1993 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Bleicher, Michael
  - Unsolved Problems, 3 folder(s)
    - 1972, June - Chromatic No. of Plane, 1966-1972 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Smith, David
    - Slither (Standard), 1971-1974 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Analyses
      Miller, George
      Anderson, L.William, Jr.
    - Slither (Misere), 1972-1997 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Santos, Bernardo
  - Walk With Dr. Matrix
    - 1969, January, 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Abramson, Harvey
  - Waring Problem (& "Easier" problem), 4 folder(s)
    - 1973, December (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Articles, bibliographies
      Shanks, Daniel
      Sluizer, Allan
    - Easier Waring's Problem [1 of 3], 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      "Tables of Solutions of the Diophantine Equation x3 + y3 = z3 -d", by V.L. Gardiner, R.B. Lazarus, & P.R. Stein, LA-5463-MS, Nov, 1973
      Stein, Paul R.
    - Easier Waring's Problem [2 of 3], 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Fuchs, Wolfgang
      Wright, Edward M.
      O'Shaughnessy, P.S.
    - Easier Waring's Problem [3 of 3], 1973-1985 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Shombert, George
      Berenson, R.S.
      Cordray, R.E.
  - Wheel, 4 folder(s)
    - 1970, September, 1960-1992 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Mostly articles & clippings on wheel
    - Wankel Engine, 1967-1977 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Clippings and articles.
    - Epi- & Hypo-Cycloids, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Analysis of Hypocycloid of Three Cusps(Gutgasz letter)
    - Cardoid & Nephroid, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Pictures, problems, articles, model
  - Word Play, 2 folder(s)
    - 1964, September (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Bird, Byron
    - Anagrams of LBJ & BMG, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      Lyndon Baines Johnson and Barry Morris Goldwater
      Owens, David
  - Worm Paths, 5 folder(s)
    - 1973, November, 1973-1985 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      Wyvill, Geoff
      Tenney, Bob
      Bell, John
    - Spirolaterals, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      Odds, Frank
      Thompson, Hugh
      Thomas, James
      Wolfram, Steven
      Foxwell, Harry
    - Mike Beeler [1 of 3], 1973 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      "Patterson's Worm", by Michael Beeler (Artificial Intelligence Memo No. 290, June 1973, MIT A.I. Laboratory)
    - Mike Beeler [2 of 3], 1973 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      Continuation of Beeler paper
    - Mike Beeler [3 of 3], 1973 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      End of paper, also microfiche of the paper, notes and correspondence abut the paper
  - Wythoff's Game & Fib. Nos., 4 folder(s)
    - 1977, March, 1977-1988 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      "A Generalizaton of Wythoff's Game", by M. E. Hoggatt, Jr, et. al. (photocopy of typescript)
    - Silber's Papers, 1976-1977 (Box 39, Folder 14)
      Reprints of Silber's articles in Fibonacci Quarterly
      Silber, Robert
    - Beatty Sequences, 1976-1978 (Box 39, Folder 15)
      Some articles by Ron Graham, by Kenneth Stolarsky, Solomon Golomb, and E.N. Gilbert
    - Fraenkel Papers on Beatty Sequences, 1977-1988 (Box 39, Folder 16)
      Description of Tsianshidsi, a generalization of Wythoff's Game
- Subject files, Series 2
  - 3 Dimensional Objects, 29 folder(s)
    - From Box 10, Folder 4: Plane Dissections (Box 73, Folder 1)
      1. 8 piece dissection of square or rhombus, from Bill Gosper
      2. 10 piece pentagram dissection and 5 piece pentagon dissection, from Gwen Roberts
      3. Tetrods, by Alex Randolph, from Ed Pegg, Jr
      4. Pentagonia (1 pentagon to 5 pentagons), from Stan Isaacs
      5. Word Pack (pack letters into rectangle), from Peter Winkler
    - From Box 10, Folder 4: Plane Dissections (Box 73, Folder 2)
      2. Trigram Set "Exploring Trigonometry with Dr. Super's Trigrams", Product # 462, Stokes Publishing Company
      3. 2D Geometric Put-Together Puzzles, from Tom McElhany
      a. Model G2 - latin cross to square Set 1G
      Model G6 - 6 point star to hexagon "
      b. Model G2 (as above)
      Model SQ2.2 - 4 piece square, 5 piece square
      c. Model G9 - square to swastika
    - From Box 13, Folder 5: Curves & Art (Equations Graphed) (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Set of postcards "Pictorial Mathematics", Series B, Nos. 1-32 (not complete)
    - From Box 14, Folder 7: Tesselations (Mosaics) [3 of 3] (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Plastic tiles, 2 pentagonal shapes, from Ed Pegg, Jr.
    - From Box 15, Folder 9: Tesselations (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Plastic shpaes from tesselations, 10 shapes, 2 of each, colored.
    - From Box 15, Folder 12: Solid Geometry (Box 73, Folder 6)
      Cardboard model of dodecahedron, advertising "The Restless Earth" television show, 10 faces with photos
    - From Box 17, Folder 1: Rotating Tetrahedral Rings (Box 73, Folder 7)
      IsoAxis - Cardboard sheet that folds to IsoAxis model
    - From Box 17, Folder 1: Rotating Tetrahedral Rings (Box 73, Folder 8)
      Tumbli - sheet of 32 triangles (plus tabs) that folds to a ring of 8 tetrahedra that rotates
    - From Box 24, Folder 10: Weighing Problems (Box 73, Folder 9)
      2 calculators for 3 false-coin puzzles, from Emmet J. Duffy
    - From Box 25, Folder 10: Weighing Problems (Box 73, Folder 10)
      15 pennies for sliding-coin puzzles, by Erik & Martin Demaine
    - From Box 27, Folder 3: Macmahon's Color Hexagons (Box 73, Folder 11)
      4 sets of Voz Tiles (7 hexagons, each of 6 out of 7 colors)
    - From Box 29, Folder 7: Necktie Paradox & Variants (Box 73, Folder 12)
      Cassette tape - radio interview with Nathan Davinsky (mathematician & chess player), including in the first section the Nectie Paradox (as: Should we exchange envelops with money.)
    - From Box 30, Folder 3: Dice Probability Problems (Box 73, Folder 13)
      Set of 3 Magic Dice (non-transitive dice)
    - From Box 33, Folder 8: Hexagonal Tessellation Games (Box 73, Folder 14)
      Hexcheckers Game (gameboard, counters, instructions)
    - From Box 47, Folder 9: Kohl, Herb (Box 73, Folder 15)
      5 inch floppy disk with polyomino demo
    - From Box 51, Folder 4: Fondos' Red/Green Device (Box 73, Folder 16)
      Mechanical model of device
    - From Box 51, Folder 13: Logic Cards (Box 74, Folder 1)
      a. Logic cards (3 kinds: Jevons' system; Red&Blue squares in square windows; circle windows)
      b. First set of T-Value cards
      c. Cards for determining all valid conclusions of any two premises
      d. Syllogis machine, by C.C. Foster
    - From Box 53, Folder 7: Pentominoes (Misc) (Box 74, Folder 2)
      Modest Polyominoes Problem Book, by Dick Hess, 1997
      Modest Hexominoes Puzzle, by Dick Hess, 1997
      Fill-Agree - A punctured polyomino puzzle, by Kate Jones
    - From Box 53, Folder 13: Hexominoes (Box 74, Folder 3)
      Complete set of green pentominoes & red hexominoes, in plastic, solved as a 15x18 rectangle
    - From Box 54, Folder 13: Polyaboloes (Box 74, Folder 4)
      Cardboard cutouts of 14 tetraboloes
    - From Box 56, Folder 1: Polyhex (Box 74, Folder 5)
      1 cardboard set of tetra-hexes
    - From Box 56, Folder 10: Magic Square Magic Tricks (Box 74, Folder 6)
      "The Ultimate Magic Square", deck of 16 cards (a number on each side) plus instructions (in German), by Christoph Wasshuber (Chris the Magician)
    - From Box 57, Folder 10: Magic Hexagons (Box 74, Folder 7)
      Magic Hexagon Puzzle (magnetic), by Signal
    - From Box 60, Folder 4: Paper Folding[2 of 3] (Box 74, Folder 8)
      Several "Rabbit in the Hat" examples
    - From Box 60, Folder 4: Paper Folding[2 of 3] (Box 74, Folder 9)
      Wire portrait of Martin Gardner, mounted on cardboard
    - From Box 74, Folder 10: Paper Cutting & Tearing (Box 74, Folder 10)
      3 folded papers, each to be cut (once)
      2 results after cut
      Result seems to be several stars, strung together
    - From Box 60, Folder 7: Paper Cutting & Tearing (Box 74, Folder 11)
      Haskell's new paper cut (3 copies)
    - From Box 60, Folder 8: Math. Origami, History of (Box 74, Folder 12)
      Package of paper for Origamics exercise
    - From Box 63, Folder 7: Japanese Puzzles (Box 74, Folder 13)